<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Analysis on Data Driven Discovery - D3</title>
    <link>https://lustrous-paprenjak-b7c3d8.netlify.app/tags/Data-Analysis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Analysis on Data Driven Discovery - D3</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://lustrous-paprenjak-b7c3d8.netlify.app/tags/Data-Analysis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Techniques for Handling Imbalanced Datasets in Machine Learning</title>
      <link>https://lustrous-paprenjak-b7c3d8.netlify.app/advanced/Advanced_Techniques_for_Handling_Imbalanced_Datasets_in_Machine_Learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lustrous-paprenjak-b7c3d8.netlify.app/advanced/Advanced_Techniques_for_Handling_Imbalanced_Datasets_in_Machine_Learning/</guid>
      <description>Advanced Techniques for Handling Imbalanced Datasets in Machine Learning Working with imbalanced datasets poses a significant challenge in machine learning, affecting the model&amp;rsquo;s performance, particularly in classification problems where the interest usually lies in the minority class. This article delves into advanced techniques for handling imbalanced datasets, offering actionable insights for both beginners and experienced practitioners in the field of data science, machine learning, data engineering, and MLOps. By employing proper strategies and methodologies, one can mitigate the bias towards the majority class, enhancing the predictive model&amp;rsquo;s overall accuracy and reliability.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beyond Accuracy: Advanced Metrics for Evaluating Machine Learning Models</title>
      <link>https://lustrous-paprenjak-b7c3d8.netlify.app/advanced/Beyond_Accuracy_Advanced_Metrics_for_Evaluating_Machine_Learning_Models/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lustrous-paprenjak-b7c3d8.netlify.app/advanced/Beyond_Accuracy_Advanced_Metrics_for_Evaluating_Machine_Learning_Models/</guid>
      <description>Beyond Accuracy: Advanced Metrics for Evaluating Machine Learning Models When it comes to evaluating machine learning models, accuracy is often the first metric that comes to mind. However, depending solely on accuracy to measure the performance of a model can be misleading, especially in cases where the dataset is imbalanced or the cost of false positives is significantly different from the cost of false negatives. In this article, we dive deep into advanced metrics beyond accuracy that provide a more nuanced understanding of model performance.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creating User-Friendly Visualizations with Tableau</title>
      <link>https://lustrous-paprenjak-b7c3d8.netlify.app/basics/Creating_User-Friendly_Visualizations_with_Tableau/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lustrous-paprenjak-b7c3d8.netlify.app/basics/Creating_User-Friendly_Visualizations_with_Tableau/</guid>
      <description>Creating User-Friendly Visualizations with Tableau Data visualization plays an essential role in the field of Data Science, Machine Learning, and Data Engineering. It not only helps in understanding patterns, trends, or insights but also makes it easier to illustrate the story behind the numbers. In this guide, we&amp;rsquo;re going to explore the role of Tableau, a widely-used data visualization tool, in creating user-friendly and interactive visualizations.
Note: Though this guide talks about Tableau, it does not include any Python or Bash code snippets since Tableau itself is a standalone tool for visualizing data.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Demystifying the Basics of Predictive Analytics</title>
      <link>https://lustrous-paprenjak-b7c3d8.netlify.app/basics/Demystifying_the_Basics_of_Predictive_Analytics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lustrous-paprenjak-b7c3d8.netlify.app/basics/Demystifying_the_Basics_of_Predictive_Analytics/</guid>
      <description>Demystifying the Basics of Predictive Analytics In the modern age where data drives decisions, predictive analytics has emerged as a game-changer for businesses, governments, and individuals alike. This article aims to demystify the fundamentals of predictive analytics for readers who are interested in the burgeoning field of data science, machine learning, and data engineering. We will take a glimpse at what predictive analytics is, its working process, its applications, as well as a some practical Python code examples using common Machine Learning libraries.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Python vs R vs SAS: Comparing Data Analysis Languages</title>
      <link>https://lustrous-paprenjak-b7c3d8.netlify.app/basics/Python_vs_R_vs_SAS_Comparing_Data_Analysis_Languages/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lustrous-paprenjak-b7c3d8.netlify.app/basics/Python_vs_R_vs_SAS_Comparing_Data_Analysis_Languages/</guid>
      <description>Python vs R vs SAS: Comparing Data Analysis Languages Data analysis is a major domain of computer science that is rapidly transforming industries globally. Numerous programming languages support data analysis, each possessing unique features, strengths, and limitations. The choice of which language to use often depends on various factors such as the specific task, industry requirements, and personal preference. In this article, we will compare three commonly used languages: Python, R, and SAS, and understand where each stands in the field of data science and machine learning.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Journey From Data to Insights</title>
      <link>https://lustrous-paprenjak-b7c3d8.netlify.app/basics/The_Journey_From_Data_to_Insights/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lustrous-paprenjak-b7c3d8.netlify.app/basics/The_Journey_From_Data_to_Insights/</guid>
      <description>The Journey From Data to Insights In this era of digital transformation, significantly influenced by the fourth industrial revolution, data is the critical fuel that powers business decision-making and strategy building. In the terrain of data, the journey from raw data to useful insights is not always easy. However, with the right set of skills, tools and techniques, one can seamlessly transform raw data into actionable insights.
The purpose of this article is to guide you through the stages of data processing and to equip you with fundamental skills such as data cleaning, data engineering, feature extraction, data modelling, and others, using machine learning libraries such as Scikit-Learn, pandas, Matplotlib etc.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Power of Deep Learning in Data Analysis</title>
      <link>https://lustrous-paprenjak-b7c3d8.netlify.app/basics/The_Power_of_Deep_Learning_in_Data_Analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lustrous-paprenjak-b7c3d8.netlify.app/basics/The_Power_of_Deep_Learning_in_Data_Analysis/</guid>
      <description>The Power of Deep Learning in Data Analysis Machine Learning and Data Science have been transforming multiple industries dramatically in recent years. Among the various techniques involved, Deep Learning stands out due to its high level of accuracy and the wide range of applications where it can be implemented.
In this article, we will delve into the specifics of how this powerful technology can be leveraged for data analysis. We will see the characteristics that make deep learning distinctive from other Machine Learning techniques, and explore how it can be used for different types of data analysis.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>TOP 10 Essential Excel Functions for Data Analysis</title>
      <link>https://lustrous-paprenjak-b7c3d8.netlify.app/basics/TOP_10_Essential_Excel_Functions_for_Data_Analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lustrous-paprenjak-b7c3d8.netlify.app/basics/TOP_10_Essential_Excel_Functions_for_Data_Analysis/</guid>
      <description>TOP 10 Essential Excel Functions for Data Analysis As a Data Professional, you stumble across a ton of data. Not all of them will be in a structured form suitable for Machine Learning or Data Science algorithms. Often, you&amp;rsquo;ll find data hidden in Excel sheets. In such cases, the ability to use Excel becomes a necessary skill to have in your repertoire. In this article, we&amp;rsquo;ll walk you through 10 invaluable Excel functions that are quintessential for Data Analysis.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Basics of SQL and its Importance</title>
      <link>https://lustrous-paprenjak-b7c3d8.netlify.app/basics/Understanding_the_Basics_of_SQL_and_its_Importance/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://lustrous-paprenjak-b7c3d8.netlify.app/basics/Understanding_the_Basics_of_SQL_and_its_Importance/</guid>
      <description>Understanding the Basics of SQL and its Importance SQL or Structured Query Language is a fundamental tool used across industries for accessing, manipulating, and analyzing data stored in relational databases. If you&amp;rsquo;re a Data professional, chances are high that you will encounter SQL. This article covers the basics of SQL and its significance in Data Science, Machine Learning, Data Engineering, and MLOps.
Introduction Despite the increasing use of NoSQL databases and newer technology stacks, SQL continues to be the dialect of choice for performing data analysis on structured data.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
